so this is The Mastermind clean and
declutter
and some people may ask well what does
that have to do with health food and
coaching right what does that have to do
with getting your body in good shape Etc
well
for me it is very very closely linked
how we are able to create our immediate
environment and I'm looking at my room
in the back here and I feel that there
is still too much clutter and we'll
we'll do the exercise here now to
quickly clean up there's a time slot in
this Mastermind where you have 10
minutes to decide on cleaning up one
corner of your house or your purse or
your bathroom for that matter but that's
in your house too
just for that experience of
creating a space around us
um
when I was teaching teachers Waldorf
teachers in particular
in Namibia
and I was proposing that we need to or I
was emphasizing and elaborating on that
we need to raise our children with more
of a con Consciousness that
I create the world so I wanted to think
or wanted to teach the teachers to for
themselves get to that sense
allow your children to feel that I
create the world
and whether that's just your tiny little
corner or whether that's a big political
Movement Like think of Nelson Mandela
or Gandhi you know I create the world
starts right here in my immediate
environment in my brain and my brain
unfortunately is so hard to read pattern
to reshape to reform and we all know
that because just like the world is
impacted by all the belief systems and
by all the patterns that were packed
upon our poor little brain when we were
babies right you've got to do this you
can't do that no no no no no no no no no
was the biggest word we heard right
cutting us down cutting us down no it's
always the boss knows best the Father
Knows Best the teacher knows best the
God knows best the
all of these systems piled upon us so
that we become
incapable or almost incapable of
actually having purpose and goals in our
life
we then have superficial goals of oh a
career I need to make this much money or
I need to have the status or I need to
have these clothes or I need to go to
this restaurant
Etc you can
see where I'm going with that right
and
[Music]
um
while
we have the illusion if you will
that we have this free will we want
freedom right freedom is the big word
we don't realize that
our world is so predestined by all these
patterns that impact Upon Our free
will because we don't develop our own
creativity enough to create the space
around us and to create the patterns in
our brain
so this sounds all very big but it's
really also very mundane because whether
I have you know I'm just going to show
you whether it has flowers on my desk
see these blue irises on my desk
um
or
whether I sit
in
pile that plates actually just thinking
of that because my son just left and he
often sits and piled up plates in his
room
foreign
because
he is not there yet where it matters to
him to create his own he will from every
other week right it's big cleanup day
but yes we all if we want to be
co-responsible for the path our life is
taking
for the health of our physical body and
of our mind then we have to learn to
repeatedly declutter those patterns
declutter the things on our desk because
yes there are the IRS is here but behind
there is a big pile and that's what I'm
going to clear up of paperwork that all
didn't get done here right and that is
just sitting there because I'm not in
need of having that I let it pile up and
that ultimately
adds to the clutter in my brain and adds
to the clutter in my life and to the
lack of clarity that can lead to what
happened to me this morning
it just went out in the last email I
sent out 10 minutes ago
I found myself crying upon waking up
for no apparent reason it's not that I'm
dying always diagnosed or I'm in pain or
uh have some other experience somebody
died nothing none of that
I'm not being evicted I'm not you know
none of nothing tragic I found myself
crying because of a lack of
clear
goals in my life right now there's so
much I'm doing I'm working from morning
to night on this on that and the other
and it doesn't have clarity
so
thankfully I have children who are
wonderful
who I can turn to who are like
therapists you know we therapize each
other
and my son was sitting with me you know
talking through what's going on Mom you
know no you can't just say I'll be fine
I'll be fine no you can't we got to talk
through this now that's also part of
that brain clearing right we need to
have people
other human beings to talk to
to put ourselves back into
perspective and into
Clarity okay what I really feel is the
most necessary thing to do what I really
know well the feeling is almost more
important than the knowing right because
uh into intellect can drive us to all
kinds of delusional
um superficial stuff you know if I make
these twenty thousand dollars and then
the other fifty thousand dollars and
then I have enough money in order to do
this big project that I always wanted to
do that's all calculation but if our
heart isn't really wanting that
we keep self-doubting even if our heart
is not not really wanting that we keep
self-doubting ourselves if we don't rain
back into a clear goal
so
a brief discussion of
what is fleeing
what
Concepts do we have of a clean
environment right
I have lived in multiple different
cultures from Germany to Switzerland to
Romania to Namibia that I just mentioned
to Zimbabwe I lived in Zimbabwe for four
and a half years and was married there
so I was very close to a very different
culture I have lived in Norway and in
Scotland and I've visited countries in
South America and so forth so I've seen
a bit of humanity and how Humanity lives
and how different cultures have
different concepts of clean
but
shocker
I found that all other cultures had more
Clarity and
and naturalness about what they
considered clean and orderly and
decluttered then
This Here country our United States
it was shocking to me that after having
lived in so many different countries and
cultures I came to a country where you
have yes you have the European concept
imported and for the wealthy you have
other people do the tidying up and the
cleaning up for us
but even some of the relatively wealthy
and as you know I'm a professor so I've
I've
started out at Columbia University
translating and working four other
professors
um
and I've been to many of their homes and
some of their homes were
so utterly
dysfunctional in terms of orderliness
and cleanliness
and that is not that that doesn't have
anything to do with sanitizing you of
sanitizing spray right
nothing to do with chlorinating anything
it has only to do with creating an
aesthetic
that mimics and goes a little bit beyond
that aesthetic that nature actually has
foreign
go out into any woods go out into any
Desert and look at the Aesthetics and
how animals keep their spaces look at a
beaver and how animals keep their spaces
right we should have those Basic
Instincts too that we keep things in an
orderly manner according to our species
of course a bird's nest is different
from a beaver beaver house I don't even
know what that's called
um or
for that matter
an elephant's
sleeping place
so
every creature on the planet has some
orderliness
and we because of our ability to self
to create
we can go beyond that and make things
extra wonderful extra and that's why we
created what
art
art is something that is completely
beyond the Aesthetics of nature right
so because we have that ability to be
creative
we also have the ability to lose that
hey Ed
you need to say hello even though I'm in
the middle of the presentation here
so
back to
what happens to human beings when we
lose that cultural hold that a
particular creativity of creating our
environment consists of
um you know people will think well you
know in Africa they're so poor they live
in these Shacks Etc
guess why
because we the Europeans took
everything away from them land culture
and belief systems
so that you know people are pushed into
these these
unsavory living environments
but here in the USFA
people almost voluntarily live in
clutter
the concept of hoarding had never
been in my realm of awareness
I haven't had never heard of such a
thing
that there's hoarding and I think it has
something to do with the lack of an old
culture you know repeating itself and
this fear of loss and you know we have
to keep it we have to keep it we have to
keep it because somebody is going to
steal it or somebody else has more or
it's a weird thing that that we have in
the North American context
of
letter
so
how can we use our own ability to
freedom to have freedom to have
creativity
to create spaces that allow us to be
mentally more clear and mentally more
directed toward the the goals the the
calling that we really think we have in
this life and I don't mean that in a
religious sense whatsoever I think
that's actually dangerous
um because in the name of religious
callings you know the Crusades had
millions of people murdered Etc and of
course you know you can extrapolate from
that
um
use our creative
abilities and our
freedom to decide
to create beautiful spaces
and I just
see in Shirley's room which I see
without Shirley in it
that something is happening there Daniel
what is happening in Shirley's face
this is not what it normally looks like
I don't know whether you all you all can
only see the speaker right yeah no we
can say you can see okay good
um
somebody took herself out
um all right so
how does that impact our sense of
accomplishment our sense of confidence
or a sense of
Direction and ultimately satisfaction
with our life you know
most of us here are not in our use
most of us here have lived and have
gathered lots of experiences
and are at a point where we would want
to
one more time put those experiences for
put them out there for a purpose right
have a purpose in
our contributing to life
so if we want to
make sense of why we accumulated all
these experiences and hopefully not all
the Clutter are only a little bit of
clutter that we can handle
um
oh Barbara says your son is wonderful
for listening to you and seeking clarity
yes yeah if we allow our children to
grow into their own it's amazing how
they become Partners in life
and we don't have to be
you know there used to be a saying you
know you should never be the friend of
your children you should always be the
parent
I think that needs to be toppled exactly
the other way around you should be a
friend of your child first
and then a parent
because when you allow your child to
express what they want seek and allow
your child to participate for example in
creating decluttering and cleaning then
they have a sense of co-responsibility
and they have a sense of I matter
and immediately the confidence is raised
there
own clarity as to what they want in life
becomes easier and they will still each
do a very different thing
my daughter is doing her PhD in
Psychology my son says Ah I don't need
to go to more of college I want to do me
now and it's perfectly fine
right you don't have to have a
a
cookie cutter approach to the contrary
if you allow creativity to rain so
what I wanted to do as an experiment in
this Mastermind is
for each and every one of you because
I've already talked for 20 minutes
to right now you can put it in the chat
what do you want to clean up clear up in
your physical environment for the next
10 minutes and then we're going to ask
what do you want to clear out in your
brain
a pattern that is holding you back that
is messing with you again and again
yeah like I was reminded this morning
um
so I already told you what my task is is
the corner of my desk where everything
is piled up so that's what I'm going to
do and I want you to decide I'm giving
you two three minutes to decide and then
I'm gonna say go and within 10 minutes
I would love it if you take a picture if
you have your phone nearby
if you're not on your phone right now or
even if you're on your phone you can do
it take a picture of
the before and then the after even what
you what we can do even in 10 minutes is
amazing
so I already took my before picture
yeah
and everybody write down
either in the chat or just for you
okay Barbara is saying my desk
okay for the 10 minutes and
and for my brain I want to decide how I
will use my time today
great
yeah every day we have that
all right
everybody knows what they want to what
they want to do then I'm going to say
one two
three
[Music]
let's put the the what to clock on
stopwatch
now
all right
oh no you see that I'm only wearing
shorts
I forgot about that
it's hot here
okay
book set in here I didn't even realize
hmm
and a big book from 2016.
[Music]
I can use that again
I think
beautiful
Beth said terrible because so many
memories and little
things come up
but
right here
only three minutes have passed that's
amazing and look at that I'm halfway
done
um
hmm
wow
here we go
going to clear eight minutes in
hey somebody asking if there will be a
recording
all right if you're getting close to
being done with your corner
come on back
so
I'm going to upload so I can show you
hmm
yeah like this
yeah I like this
and
some reason
there we go
here we go okay
and this is the after
all right
are you all back
our 10 minutes are up
let me see
yeah we're at 11.
so
is that a crazy little experiment
Ed what did you do
you need to unmute yourself we can't
hear you
just clearing out some stuff off my
phone yes Bravo that is awesome because
that's another way we clutter right we
have this phone full of stuff and we're
endlessly scrolling yeah Rubble
excellent idea
um okay uh Joanna yes Lynn uh Shirley
what did you decide that my wet macular
degeneration I've uh accumulated
a lot of notebook paper and then I write
little notes on envelopes and then it's
hard for me to read if I write too fast
I was a beautiful writer before so what
did you do to declutter
well I was just trying to put the aiming
to put the envelopes
uh together and then the notebook paper
but uh I can't do the computer like I
was so fast and I had a masters in
technology before but because of my eyes
this is hard and I was very I did very
goal orientated all my life
interdirected
that is wonderful so but you still tried
to tidy up your envelopes Right add my
notebook paper and your notebook paper
wonderful and for everybody to know
Shirley is in her mid-80s and a very
active young lady
yes and let me pace for a minute
oh you don't have the camera
no my uh face uh I during covet I
neglected my teeth because of my Hut
taking care of my husband I know okay we
we forgive you it's all good I just
wanted to show everybody your 80 80 how
old are you now 85 86
I'm going to uh yes 86 I'm going to be
87 and I am
I'm still raw foods
you eat a lot of raw food cool that is
so beautiful all right so
um yeah I just had another conversation
with Nancy um Gordon another client of
mine who's not here today but is going
to watch this later who's 87 and still
walks up and down
down to the Hudson River and back up to
her house which is like a mile you know
up the hill
um all right Barbara what did you do
you need to unmute yourself
doesn't work
okay
when you get there
um Linda Linda what did you do
um I organized some papers that I have
with me I'm I actually am sitting in my
parked car I had to drive someplace
where I could hook up to Wi-Fi
so I'm roasting in the hot car oh open
all your windows
so I just worked on whatever I had with
me
gotcha wonderful and Janet what did you
do
well most important of all I I found
money
um I found a check that's actually not
for me but it's for a friend that used
to stay here and I still get a lot of
mail for her and this I had opened and
told her about and I thought I sent it
to her but apparently I didn't because I
just found a check and I also found two
important pieces of mail one for me and
one for my husband that from um IRS
saying we had some sort of additional
refund coming uh at least that's what
mine said his wasn't opened
and um other than that I I took pales
and and sorted them uh and so it's much
more organized right now it doesn't look
better but it is a lot more organized
than it was and I have a big pile to
file
which is always my problem I have a lot
of problems or a lot of piles some in
boxes and things that are really to file
and I never get around to that yeah I'm
going to talk about you know how we can
help ourselves with all of that in a
minute so I'm going to just wonderful so
everybody did actually find something
physically to clear and Barbara texted
that she also did her desk right yeah
oh now I can hear you yes yeah I I
texted my desk and I have a lot of
things wired to my my uh wired things
and I untangled all the wires that are
connected to my computer so that's good
wonderful so yes and how good it feels
how much we can get done in just 10
minutes so I'm going to show you that
I'm going to try and share the before
and after of my
desk here that corner can you see the
pile of papers here
all right that's the before
and
now I'm going to go to the after
where's the after
oh
let me see oh I have to separately
separately do it yes
honest
Post-its
and
here is the after picture see how clear
that corner is all gone that whole pile
and it actually wasn't very difficult to
sort it into where it needs to go in my
various systems
so
great okay now don't we all wish that it
were as easy to clear the clutter in our
brain not just clutter but the old
patterns that keep coming back and grasp
us what kind of patterns are there that
have a hold on us
um can you give me some suggestions
either in the chat or
just unmute yourself and talk
I might need this
that kind of things we say to ourselves
like I might need this yes
the things we say to ourselves
um
yeah what what comes from the past what
comes from our past patterns
from our childhood
don't
waste don't waste it don't waste oh you
you're talking about Gathering things
and keeping things because we're not
wasting them yes okay that was I might
need this sir now I'm putting it into
context yes I might need this so let me
keep this and before we know it we've
hoarded all sorts of stuff that are just
cluttering up our spaces right and at
the same time they're cluttering up our
brain because our brain constantly
starts to try and figure well how can I
use this what can I make with this right
and just to give you an example from me
of course
um but I also mean patterns like
never being praised for what you do as a
child you know my parents were of the
opinion praise is to make or my
especially my my grandmother actually
more than my parents you know if I give
you a praise it's going to make you
conceded or too proud and pride was like
a really bad thing in her eyes you know
right so don't praise just criticize so
that they're always trying to get better
right and what happens then is we
self-criticize all the time it becomes
smaller and smaller and smaller and
[Music]
so
yeah I like to be very graphic
um yeah so that's that's a pattern right
that we self-doubt all the time because
we were raised like that does anybody
else have patterns like that from
childhood
oh yes
most of us are probably at the age of
that mentality from
parents that were in war times and
things when we had to collect and save
and just in case and all those things
yes and how about the self-confidence
especially for
um
yeah of Our Generation
I guess uh it's damaged from that
mm-hmm
what about you Ed what kind of patterns
do you find in your brain that hold you
back
unmute
unmute unmute and mute unmute unmute
yeah I think hoarding from my
brought on from my parents generation as
well yeah
also hoarding yeah yeah
very clear
thing around you but we don't see much
maybe the rest of the place yeah on the
side there I'm trying to look around the
corner yeah
yeah Barbara can you do sign language
oh I can talk now
yeah no I mean I'm I mean no I know I
can't do that because I'm looking for
somebody who I have a client who wants
their daughter who signs you know to
take um the um
the the coaching class that I teach but
I need to find somebody who can
translate so I just
just outside
right I'll ask my teenage friend uh who
if she knows enough sign to do that for
you wonderful
so yeah
um those patterns
but also the patterns
of
yeah the self-doubt for me is a very big
thing and the patterns of
um well I'm just being lazy I'm
I I don't
I don't know enough how to do this
I guess one of the aspects of that is
imposter syndrome right I'm just not
good enough who am I to go out there and
talk and or
think that I have all this knowledge
um and then
we don't Implement another pattern I
think is that goes with the hoarding
that all of you seem to have some of
um
is accumulating learning learning
learning and never taking action to
actually use right on our own
initiatives right or always waiting for
somebody to tell us what to do because
we're set we're in our generation
especially we're so used to being told
what to do and what not to do that and
always to learn and so you know we take
all these online courses and watch these
videos and right or we take another
course at the University and
and it's never good enough for some
reason for us to take action and
implement
and of course that's particularly true
when we are at retirement age and we
were used to being employed and having a
job to fulfill and now we want to do all
these new things but
we don't know how to self-initiate
and that just I want to give you a
little example you know for people for
whom it's even harder
I just um my my friends at my house who
had running a craft show and they
brought their 21 year old autistic son
with them
and he is not very good at looking after
himself but he's very verbal and he can
be very funny and so he has great
qualities
um also great memory Etc
but
he said to me in the car when I said you
know when he said you know my father
always wants me to talk to the customers
you know because they're at this crafts
fair and of course you know people come
by and in droves and you're supposed to
engage the potential customers and for
an autistic child that is really really
difficult because there's always that
socialization
um anxiety
so he was saying you know my father
wants me to
to talk to people and I can talk when
somebody talks to me but I have such a
hard time initiating I just can't
initiate a conversation
and I thought to myself that's exactly
you know what we're all struggling with
it's just even more in an autistic child
because the brain is in in many cases
um
chemically injured
as a child and and or you know just
configured
like that
um so
we all have some of that right that fear
of initiating an activity whether it's
talking to a stranger or whether it's
going and actually buying the stuff that
we now want to eat for our healthy
healthier food or whether it's deciding
I'm going to
um allow myself to go get a massage
because it's good for me or because or
whatever it is or
I'm going to get into this business I'm
becoming a whatever it is and yeah one
of my clients is just
um saying I think I'm going to go into
this networking business but I still
have to initiate and talk to more people
because every time
I promote the product right I have to
talk to new people and I just said well
we could also say and it's interesting
that one of my clients in my last uh 12
month class was saying that
you know actually all of life is sales
because we're always sharing something
of our own and or getting something from
the other person whether it's a service
or a smile or a good or a bread or
whatever it is right or a piece of
clothing all of life is sales
if we
so once we get to that understanding we
no longer have the fear of saying I have
this to offer do you want this
oh sorry I made somebody wait here
who's coming on
um
hi Mary unmute yourself and say hello so
we're way in but you can catch up on the
Rest by listening to the recording so we
are at the brain decluttering phase of
this Mastermind rain decluttering being
very much more complicated than the
physical decluttering which we all
manage to do brilliantly everybody did
it which is
unusual so good we had nobody saying ah
I'm not doing that that was pretty neat
so yeah
the brain decluttering
involves learning to take initiative
learning to take action to actually
change habits so that a new imprint can
happen in our brain
years ago when I was called to co-found
a new type of school
or
ADHD and dyslexic children
you know who need a much more creative
approach much more engaged approach but
many of whom are very highly gifted
um I was talking to experts like brain
and experts and neurology experts and
there's this one brain scientist Dr
gerhardt future in in Germany
who um
explained that
every time we create a new physical
pattern in our life and this is where
the two sides come together that's why
we're doing the physical exercise and
the mental one
every time we physically change a
pattern in our life
literally our neural Pathways in the
brain are reconfigured right
and I think that it's just so
important to realize you know that with
everything we physically do we impact
our physical brain and there with our
mental abilities and our mental
functioning
and of course it also works the other
way around but it's harder to get that
done every time we change our mental
attitude it's easier to do physical
things right or different
um for the physical Behavior
but it's much easier and that's why now
many
psychologists are also realizing that
allowing people to get physically
involved in something for example
helping other people you know there's
this famous book that my daughter read
when she was 12 and then read many times
it's kind of her Baseline for her
studies in psychology
it's called Reviving Ophelia
and it's about these young girls
working with a psychologist who are
self-destructive for anorexic or cutting
themselves or have survived suicide
attempts Etc when they get physically
involved in working in soup kitchens in
working in in in the hospice helping old
people clean their butts and helping you
know when it's when we get physically
involved and engaged in meaningful new
patterns
our mental stability
benefits
and we re-pattern our own and I think I
should apply that to my experience this
morning you know waking up crying
um
because there isn't enough
pattern and active involvement in my
life right now
to
re-pattern for the next big project last
year at this time I was creating
[Music]
the university that we're building and
right now it's on ice because we need to
raise the money to put the first
online classes into action so that's the
that's the position where we are
when we
physically help ourselves clarify clean
and declutter our brain and mentality
clear and declutter as well or have an
easier time doing so all right so let's
do one more little exercise and we're
over our time already but
and that is
there's also a part of our brain that
just
rebalances itself when we allow it to
just happen or we pose a question
and we see what answer
comes while we just relax into a kind of
a meditative state for a couple of
minutes
and before we go into this exercise I
need to put it out there of course that
everybody is invited to join the June
Rejuvenation which is a lot of the
physical stuff the fitness the making
the smoothies the
finding food that in the wild that has
better energy Etc and the planning of
life in the super happy body class that
is the focus on what am I going to do
for the next five years so everybody is
invited to talk to me personally to how
any of those programs would benefit you
if you wanted to
so
and I mean you all have my
email address if you're getting my
emails
you can just respond to those or put in
the chat that you would like a spot for
a one-on-one consultation I do these
um free 20-minute consultations
that we can
offer it so that you can figure out
where it might be helpful for you to
participate
all right now we're going to each ask
ourselves
where do I want to be next year at this
time
and if you have two options you know put
those two options out there well I could
either do this or that
or if you have one option just put that
out there and ask yourself how will I
get there what's the next step
and then don't
um
don't analyze calculate and do the
numbers so to speak but just allow
yourself to
relax into that question
and see what comes up sometimes very
bizarre people come up bizarre things or
people come up when people ask these
questions
and
and then we'll we'll talk about it and
I'm going to give us just
two minutes yeah my instinct is just two
minutes okay and we're gonna start
now
of course take some deep breaths
and then ask the questions
where will I be
next year
or do I want to be
oh the stuff that comes up right away
I did not think so
interesting
foreign
yeah
too long leads into thinking and that's
not what we want to do we don't want to
think we just want to allow things to
appear
and
here it is
now there are of course various ways of
allowing our brain to sort itself out in
this manner I used to
when I had two options or more
or a path to pursue over the next time I
would go to bed with the question and
would ask my brain or my spirit you know
whatever you want to call it to figure
it out and I'll wake up knowing right
so we can also do that and if you do
that several days it will clarify it
will clear itself
um
so this one was interesting does anybody
want to start or do you want to hear why
I was laughing
and we want to hear while you why you
were laughing
[Laughter]
well I'm 69.
and going to be 70 in a couple of months
but I am embarking on a new relation not
so new but on a relationship that is
getting serious and my first image came
up was a lovely situation with this new
relationship
so
that
how to get there is there is the big
question but that seemed very clear that
that is what
is maybe priority
and of course life has to organize
itself around that
yeah
all right what came up that was
surprising for you guys you know I have
all these projects but it's it's
interesting to me even that the
relationship came up as the first thing
um this is Jan Janet um I was surprised
right away it came up well gee look what
you did in 10 minutes
if if you could just discipline yourself
to take even 15 20 minutes a day and do
this every day and then maybe a little
more time on Saturday or Sunday days you
have more time more free time think you
know how how wonderful life could be
I have
um
you know little piles and too much of
everything all over the house that we
live in but we also have an addict that
is just completely full of stuff mostly
a lot from my family memorabilia that
was kind of passed on to me because
nobody else wanted it and whatever and I
mean I just can't imagine how in the
rest of my life I can get that done and
I had a professional organizer come in
and I'm not willing to pay what that's
going to cost because if I just set my
mind to it I can do it
there you go but you know what we all
need we all need accountability Partners
yeah and why this worked here in this
circle is because we held each other
accountable
right because we knew we were going to
have to talk about having done it
so accountability Partners is what we in
all coaching and learning and
professorial of course circles need
right if my students
know that I'm going to read their papers
and they have to complete them by a
certain time they will do it if I never
have any interest in what they do
they're much less likely to do it
and that goes that's a lifelong
situation so find yourself an
accountability partner or talk to me
about how to how to create that
accountability and make it fun
yes and as you can absolutely you can do
it you know as we just saw that's so
cool in 10 minutes it gave you that
Insight beautiful
so
Mary you came in late but are you
getting what we're doing
unmute yourself for a minute
Mary are you there
ask to unmute
no okay we'll we're gonna have to skip
Mary
Ed what came up for you
um I think to
declutter your mind
you have to remove the stresses from
your nervous system so yes it means a
continual
regular meditation program to to
accomplish this and I've been doing that
and I will continue to do that through
taking Advanced meditation techniques
which I've been doing now so
wonderful but all the meditation doesn't
help if you don't take action well you
are taking action by meditating twice a
day that is your action and the rest
just falls into place
so the rest of your house is going to
clear up oh
no that'll
that will have to
when you find the time that's the thing
it's all about priorities right yeah
what's important in your life now yes
yeah
absolutely
so
where do you want to be next next year a
year from now
um probably further along
the path to enlightenment
okay that's your priority yeah then
that's that's your priority wonderful
what are you going to do with that
Enlightenment is always my question for
people who want just Enlightenment for
enlightenment's sake well Enlightenment
is a lifelong process or several
lifetime process yeah and it'll get you
it'll clearly put your your focuses are
which
is not materialistic it's
the other aspect the spiritual aspects
of life
and that's what I think is important and
too many people are focused on the
materialize materialistic aspects and
they it totally ignore the spiritual
aspects because how to achieve it yeah
yes and I hear you loud and clear
let me add this
if I know myself as a spiritual being
right
I understand myself as that spiritual
being having the want having had the
want to Incarnate and be here in this
lifetime on this planet using the
material environments to
impact life and Humanity on this planet
while I'm here for this lifetime
so the next step then is once you have
that spiritual understanding to again
take action in your physical existence
because you know I can do all the
non-physical stuff when I'm not here
because in a couple of decades I won't
be here right right
so I can do all of that when I'm not on
planet Earth but now I'm here and here
are all my co-humans and all my fellows
and and friends and sisters and brothers
and
I want to
use this opportunity of having an
Earthly experience
to see how I can help Humanity
move forward into a direction of course
that you and I probably agree needs to
become a more peaceful more joyful more
collaborative world as opposed to a
warring contradictory competitive you
know
um you either either master or the slave
type of attitude
so
that's what I just wanted to add it's
wonderful to achieve that spiritual
understanding I am
an incredible being
but right now you have decided to be
edwardinsky on planet Earth
and you have a job to do to be the best
edwardinsky you can ever be
right
beautiful okay our atmosphere Your
Atmosphere affects the people around you
yes if you are positive you you send out
positive vibes to the people around you
if you are negative you send out
negative Vibes and the goal is for
everyone to be sending out positive
vibes and right now in this earth cycle
there are too many negative
people negative Vibes that are going out
and that's what's creating all these
wars tension and everything and we've
got to reverse that process now yeah we
gotta move well I say not reverse
because we're moving forward you know
time only works in One Direction yes and
we've got to take all that old knowledge
that we could have and use it in order
to move Humanity forward beautiful all
right and maybe that's your action to
just create peace peaceful energy
in your immediate environment beautiful
yeah all right now
Janie we haven't heard from you and
Linda we haven't heard from you can you
also share
Linda and Janie
there's Linda okay hi I actually had
just sent a chat that I need to sign off
and um
I sent it I meant to send it to everyone
but I sent it to you Joanna but
including everyone
[Music]
um
am I still oh yes we are on
um I don't really have anything to add
right now because I I have to sign off I
have to leave the meeting okay I wanted
to thank you Joanna and everyone
and it's uh it's getting more
interesting now too with all this
discussion
um but I I need to go all right you can
always listen to the recording
okay
all right I will send it to you thank
you Joanna and thank you to everyone who
participated
um bye Linda bye bye hope you all have a
good rest of your holiday weekend you
too and thanks for being here thank you
all right bye-bye ciao
all right
Janie would you like to participate
and
Shirley are you still with us
that's just if if something specific
came up for you where do you want to be
next year from now in a year from now
yeah
you'd have to unmute yourself and if
that doesn't work surely we're going to
go to Barbara
where do you want to be in a year from
now what came out of you okay
um I wrote
um
well I uh
I'm I'm trying to commit myself to a
macrobiotic lifestyle I hope to have my
habits in place my routines my cooking
routines and my self-care and exercise
and all of all the lifestyle that that
promotes health and well-being I hope to
have them in place a structure so that
it's easy and natural
wonderful and I can certainly help you
get put that structure in place if you
want so we we should have that that 30
minute
um session 20 30 minutes
so that
um
there's more clarity on that right so
Janet already knows she wants to clean
out her attic
and again we can make that happen in a
year or less as you just saw right you
don't need the next decade for that as
you suggested
yeah and because I have a hoarding
disorder problem uh I want to have that
man handled mostly you know major major
uh Improvement in by one year from now
yes that will unburden me and unstress
me if I've handled that
and then I want to have more time to do
enjoyable things with friends yes and
you know what Barbara that's the
interesting thing
the hoarding comes out of a lack of
spending time with community and friends
and it comes out of a lack of
celebrating each other and celebrating
life
right and that is something that I
realized also you know when I first
encountered hoarders in this United
States I came to the United States in
um actually from my life in Zimbabwe via
Europe again but yeah you know I had to
spend four and a half years in Zimbabwe
and worked there and had my business
there
and was married there
so
seeing both the very rural life in
Zimbabwe in in you know even a crowd
with round Huts Etc everything is
beautifully organized and there's
patterns to everything the way you eat
the way you greet you know I learned the
greeting and I learned all the you know
sayings
and um
and when you lack that community and
those patterns of behavior in not just
nuclear family but a greater communal
setting right
then those voids that our human needs
are filled with stuff right right we
accumulate stuff
instead of accumulating
celebrated celebrations and experiences
I agree I agree so switch it around
exactly so now you're going to get more
of that communal celebration with your
friends and you won't need the other
clutter exactly yes wonderful all right
great
okay
um again I want to invite everybody to
make a use of that 30-minute session
that you can have with me 20 minutes 30
minutes whatever you need
and I'll send an email out to the people
who were here today
to invite you to that with a link where
you can sign up for a time slot
and of course you know check out again
how much the whole program of the June
Rejuvenation can help you or which parts
can be useful to you
and I will see you all in the next time
I see you and Barbara for you I can
actually have an in-person meeting with
you because you're local I love that
yeah for sure you know you can you can
come to a pot like dinner at my house or
something like that yeah and Ed you are
in Canada right
in
yeah
which which part oh uh Calgary Alberta
Alberta right yeah
um
you have an interesting new governor
right who's
um is that a governor or oh a premier
the the election is actually tomorrow
okay great yeah
interesting so I I hope
you get the person that you desire right
will do a good job for more peacefulness
and more
and less oppression yeah
wonderful uh my thoughts are with you
there thanks yeah I've looked into it
okay and Mary and Janet and Shirley
and everybody else who was here briefly
but whom we didn't see
um
let's all continue on this path of
learning how to clear
declutter the world around us because
that helps us with the world inside of
us
and thank you for being here it
certainly helped me do my little
decluttering and get over the crying
this morning even more because that is
what happens we get lost
when we are too
fogged up
and when we clear
we see
what the future looks like or what we
want the future to look like and we can
actively move toward it all right the
next Mastermind is going to be on
something very mundane in comparison
what's in your raw salad
and that's next Sunday so if you want to
make interesting and cleansing and
wonderfully delicious raw salads join me
again next Sunday in what's in your raw
salad
thank you all right thank you everybody
lots of love and
see you soon ciao all right back at you
wonderful thank you